Guide to the Richard W. Gilkey Photographs 1947-2005
Oregon State University Libraries, University Archives
Richard W. Gilkey Photographs
1947-2005
1947-1953
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center University Archives 121 The Valley Library Oregon State University Corvallis, OR 97331-4501 Phone: 541-737-2165 Email: archives@oregonstate.edu Web: http://osulibrary.oregonstate.edu/archives
P 252
Gilkey, Richard William, 1930-
1 cubic foot, including 1050 photographs 5 boxes, including 1 oversize box
The Richard W. Gilkey Photographs consist of images made by Gilkey during his student years at Oregon State College in the late 1940s and early 1950s. The photographs provide extensive documentation of student life; many were published in the Beaver yearbook and the Oregon Stater alumni magazine. Gilkey earned BS and MS degrees from Oregon State.
Biographical Note:
Richard W. Gilkey attended Oregon State College from 1948 to 1953 and earned his BS in Science Education in 1951 and MS in Education in 1953. He was one of the first student photographers to document campus life in an official university capacity; many of his photographs were published in the Beaver yearbooks and Oregon Stater alumni magazine. He also worked as a stringer photographer for the Oregon Journal newspaper in Portland. He co-founded with other students, the Memorial Union Camera Club, which held an annual Spring Salon.
Gilkey was Supervisor of Audiovisual Education for the Portland Public Schools beginning in 1966 and Director of Educational Media from 1972 until his retirement in 1993.
The Archives developed an exhibit of his work that was held on campus in 2005 during the Golden Jubilee reunion weekend.
The Richard W. Gilkey Photographs consist of images made by Gilkey during his student years at Oregon State College. The photographs provide extensive documentation of student life and campus activities and include images of athletic facilities, events, athletes, and coaches; clubs, student organizations, fraternities, and sororities; dances and special events in the Memorial Union, such as the annual Christmas party; drama productions; student outings, such as canoeing on the Marys River; homecoming events; and commencement.
The collection includes images of the exteriors and interiors of many campus buildings. The Memorial Union, Library (Kidder Hall), Gill Coliseum, and Sackett Hall are well represented.
Of special note are a series of portraits of nine faculty made by Gilkey that were published as covers of the Oregon Stater alumni magazine in 1952-1953. Prints of these images made by Gilkey in 2005 are part of the collection. The Gilkey Photographs depict many students at Oregon State during the late 1940s and early 1950s; some, but not all, of the images of students are identified with their names.
Many of Gilkey's photographs were published in the Beaver yearbook, Oregon Stater alumni magazine, and Barometer campus newspaper as well as Paste Up at "State", the Tech Record, and Memorial Union and student organization publications. Paste Up at "State" was a pictorial magazine about students and student activities published by Oregon State students in November 1948.
The bulk of the collection is negatives. Most of the film negatives are 3.25 x 4.25 inches; the collection also includes 4x5 in negatives and a few individual frames of 120 film. Silver gelatin prints and digital prints are also part of the collection. Most of the prints were made in 2004-2005 for the exhibit.
Collection is open for research.
The Richard W. Gilkey Photographs are arranged in 16 series: I. College Track, 1948; II. College Basketball, 1947-1952; III. College Football, 1947-1951; IV. College Baseball, 1948; V. Spot News, 1948; VI. Barometer, 1947-1951; VII. Paste Up at "State" and Other Publications, 1948-1949; VIII. Miscellaneous, 1949; IX. Dances, 1948; X. Memorial Union, circa 1950; XI. Oregon Stater, 1948-2005; XII. News Bureau, 1948-1951; XIII. Campus Buildings, circa 1950; XIV. Campus Views, circa 1950; XV. Unnumbered Color Transparencies, 1949; XVI. Documentary Materials, 1947-2005.
The materials were donated by Gilkey to the Archives in 2004 and 2005.
Richard Gilkey's photographs are part of many other collections in the Archives' holdings, including the Football Photographs (P 004), Alumni Association Photographs (P 017), and Harriet's Collection. An oral history interview of Gilkey is part of the Oregon State University Alumni Oral History Collection (OH 13). Extensive documentation of the Oregon Stater alumni magazine is available in the Alumni Association Records (RG 035). More recent photographs published in the Oregon Stater are available in the Oregon Stater Photographs (P 195).
Oregon State College--Faculty.; Oregon State College--Students.
College buildings--Oregon--Corvallis.; College environment--Oregon--Corvallis.; College sports--Oregon--Corvallis.; College student newspapers and periodicals--Oregon--Corvallis.; College students--Oregon--Corvallis.; Greek letter societies--Oregon--Corvallis.; Student activities--Oregon--Corvallis.; Student housing--Oregon--Corvallis.
Color transparencies.; Film negatives.; Photographic prints.
Colleges and Universities; Sports and Recreation; Student Life; Women; Oregon; Corvallis; Photographs
- College Track, 1948; Series I; 8 negatives
  Series I consists of photographs of the 1948 Oregon State track meet versus the University of Oregon.
  - OSC vs. Oregon, May 15, 1948; SpCT-001 - SpCT-003; 3 negatives (Box 1)
  - Rassmussin, May 15, 1948; SpCT-004 - SpCT-006; 4 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Oregon, May 15, 1948; SpCT-007 (Box 1)
- College Basketball, 1947-1952; Series II; 112 negatives
  Series II consists of photographs of basketball games.
  - OSC vs. Portland University, November 28, 1947; SpCBk-001 - SpCBK-003; 3 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Linfield, SpCBk-004 - SpCBk-006; 3 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Portland University, January 2, 1948; SpCBk-007 - SpCBk-009; 3 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Oregon, January 19, 1948; SpCBk-010 (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Oregon, January 11, 1948; SpCBk-011 (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Oregon, January 17, 1948; SpCBk-012 (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Oregon, January 17, 1948; SpCBk-013 (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Washington, January 30, 1948; SpCBk-014 - SpCBk-019; 5 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Washington, January 30, 1948; SpCBk-020 - SpCBk-022; 3 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Idaho, February 16, 1948; SpCBk-023 - SpCBk-024; 2 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Idaho, SpCBk-025 - SpCBk-026; 2 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Idaho, February 17, 1948; SpCBk-027 - SpCBk-030; 4 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Oregon, February 20, 1948; SpCBk-031 - SpCBk-034; 4 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Oregon, February 21, 1948; SpCBk-035 - SpCBk-038; 4 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Washington State College, February 27, 1948; SpCBk-039 - SpCBk-043; 5 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Washington State College, February 28, 1948; SpCBk-044 - SpCBk-046; 3 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Oregon, March 6, 1948; SpCBk-047 - SpCBk-054; 8 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Willamette University, December 10, 1948; SpCBk-055 - SpCBk-058; 4 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Utah, SpCBk-059 - SpCBk-062; 4 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Indiana, SpCBk-063 - SpCBk-071; 8 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Minnesota, SpCBk-072 - SpCBk-078; 6 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Washington State College, SpCBk-079 - SpCBk-082; 4 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Oregon, SpCBk-083 - SpCBk-090; 8 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Washington, SpCBk-091 - SpCBk-096; 9 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Oregon, SpCBk-097 - SpCBk-104; 8 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Washington State College, January 4, 1952; SpCBk-105; 7 negatives (Box 1)
- College Football, 1947-1951; Series III; 147 negatives
  The College Football photographs include images of several football games as well as halftime activities with the marching band and cheerleaders.
  - Oregon State vs. University of Portland freshman, SpCF-001 (Box 1)
  - OSU Rooks vs. University of Portland frosh, SpCF-002 - SpCF-003; 2 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Washington State College, 1947; SpCF-004 - SpCF-006; 3 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Idaho, 1948; SpCF-007 - SpCF-012; 6 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Washington, 1948; SpCF-013 - SpCF-019; 7 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Portland, 1948; SpCF-020 -SpCF-027; 8 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Michigan State College, October 30, 1948; SpCF-029 - SpCF-034; 6 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Utah, November 13, 1948; SpCF-035 - SpCF-038; 4 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Oregon, November 20, 1948; SpCF-039 - SpCF-044; 6 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Nebraska, November 27, 1948; SpCF-045 - SpCF-048; 4 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. California, 1949; SpCF-049 - SpCF-052 (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Washington in Seattle, 1949; SpCF-053 - SpCF-062; 8 negatives (Box 1)
    Image SpCF-054 shows Oregon State player Carpenter preventing Washington touchdown by knocking down a pass from Don O'Leary to Darold Falkey in the end zone.
  - OSC vs. Washington State College, SpCF-063 - SpCF-071; 9 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Michigan State College, 25-20, SpCF-072 - SpCF-079; 9 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Oregon, 20-10, SpCF-081 - SpCF-089; 9 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Stanford, SpCF-090; 7 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Washington, SpCF-091; 12 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. California, SpCF-092 - SpCF-102; 11 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Oregon, SpCF-103 - SpCF-115; 13 negatives (Box 1)
  - Football halftime, SpCF-116; 2 negatives (Box 1)
  - Football halftime - Seattle, 1951; SpCF-117; 7 negatives (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. UCLA, SpCF-118; 5 negatives (Box 1)
  - Unidentified football game (Dick Galling), 7 negatives (Box 1)
- College Baseball, 1948; Series IV; 13 negatives
  Series IV consists of photographs of 1948 baseball games against the University of Washington and the University of Oregon.
  - OSC vs. Washington, SpCBa-001 - SpCBa-007; 7 negatives
    - April 26, 1948, SpCBa-001 (Box 1)
    - First baseman Bob Christianson does the splits while putting out University of Washington baserunner Sammy White., April 26, 1948; SpCBa-002 (Box 1)
    - April 26, 1948, SPCBa-003 (Box 1)
    - April 27, 1948, SCPBa-004 (Box 1)
    - April 27, 1948, SpCBa-005 (Box 1)
    - Bob Christianson is Oregon State first baseman., April 27, 1948; SpCBa-006 (Box 1)
    - April 27, 1948, SpCBa-007 (Box 1)
  - OSC vs. Oregon, SpCBa-008 - SpCBa-013; 6 negatives
    - SpCBa-008 (Box 1)
    - SpCBa-009 (Box 1)
    - SpCBa-010 (Box 1)
    - SpCBa-011 (Box 1)
    - Baseball field during game, SpCBa-012 (Box 1)
    - SpCBa-013 (Box 1)
- Spot News, 1948; Series V; 14 photographs
  The Spot News photographs document the student rally in support of basketball coach Slats Gill held in spring 1948 when the campus community learned that Gill was being considered for open coaching positions at UCLA and the University of Minnesota.
  - Slats Gill on Porch at Rally, NS-001 (Box 1)
  - Petition Being Presented at Rally, March 1948; NS-002
    - negative (Box 1)
    - digital print (Box 3)
  - Crowd at Gill Rally, March 1948; NS-003 - NS-013; 11 negatives (Box 1)
- Barometer, 1947-1951; Series VI; 100 negatives
  The Barometer photographs depict a variety of campus events and student activities including homecoming, student elections, international students, music groups, theater productions, and dances. The Freedom Train, which housed documents pertaining to United States history, visited Corvallis during its nationwide tour.
  - Hudson Hall Homecoming Sign, PuB-001; 2 negatives (Box 1)
  - Barber Shop Quartet, PuB-002 (Box 1)
  - College Choir, PuB-003 - PuB-004; 2 negatives
    - PuB-003 (Box 1)
    - PuB-004 (Box 1)
  - OSC Ski Team, PuB-005 (Box 1)
  - Preminodiers Club, 1948; PuB-006; 3 negatives (Box 1)
  - Northwest College Conference Officers for 1947/1948, ca. 1948; PuB-007; 2 negatives (Box 1)
  - R. G and looks at documents, PuB-008 (Box 1)
  - Dedication Week Parade, 1948; PuB-009 (Box 1)
  - Crowd Entering Freedom Train, 1948; PuB-010 (Box 1)
  - Freedom Train, April 1948; PuB-011 (Box 1)
  - Freedom Train Lineup, 1948; PuB-012; 2 negatives (Box 1)
  - Sophomore Show, 1948; PuB-013 - PuB-016; 4 negatives (Box 1)
  - Little Come Kanidates, PuB-017; 3 negatives (Box 1)
  - Ag Jamboree Queen, 1948; PuB-018; 2 negatives (Box 1)
  - Play - State of the Union, PuB-019 - PuB-021; 3 negatives (Box 1)
  - Mortar Board, 1947-1948; PuB-022; 4 negatives (Box 1)
  - Glass Blowing Club, April 8, 1948; Pub-023; 2 negatives (Box 1)
  - Sadie Hawkins Day, 1948; PuB-024 - PuB-029; 6 negatives (Box 1)
    PuB-024 available online.
  - Nursery School, 1948; PuB-030 (Box 1)
  - Betas Practicing for Interfraternity Sing, PuB-031; 2 negatives (Box 1)
  - Squaring the Circle, 1948; PuB-032 - PuB-034; 3 negatives (Box 1)
  - Scarboard and Blade Flag Raising Ceremony, PuB-035; 2 negatives (Box 1)
  - Ben Howe, PuB-036; 4 negatives (Box 1)
  - Freshman Week Committee Pictures for Fall 1948 Barometer, PuB-046; 2 negatives (Box 1)
  - Homecoming Princesses, 1948; PuB-047; 2 negatives (Box 1)
  - Background for Queen Pictures in Homecoming Issue, PuB-051 (Box 1)
  - Card Section Committee, PuB-054; 2 negatives (Box 1)
  - Crowd at Utah Game, PuB-055; 2 negatives (Box 1)
  - "Buck" Dorthery, PuB-057; 4 negatives (Box 1)
  - Free Stater Presidential Candidates, PuB-058; 4 negatives (Box 1)
  - Camera Club Field Trip, PuB-059 (Box 1)
  - Sue Barns Washing a Pig, PuB-060; 2 negatives (Box 1)
  - Vaughn Monroe, PuB-061 - PuB-067; 6 negatives (Box 1)
  - Homecoming Committee, PuB-068; 2 negatives (Box 1)
  - Foreign Students Round Table, PuB-069; 3 negatives (Box 1)
  - Mayhem, 1951; PuB-070; 5 negatives (Box 1)
  - Beaver Sales Drive, 1951; PuB-071 (Box 1)
  - Beaver Publicity, PuB-072; 9 negatives (Box 1)
    One image available online.
- Paste Up at "State" and Other Publications, 1948-1949; Series VII; 89 photographs
  Series VII includes many of the images that were published in the 1948 Paste Up at "State" publication as well as images for other publications. The photographs document student activities and events as well as campus buildings.
  - Bolter Twins, PuX-055 - PuX-056; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Bob Carl, PuX-057 - PuX-058; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Formals (Group), PuX-082 - PuX-083; 4 negatives (Box 2)
  - Bathing Suit Group, PuX-087 (Box 2)
  - Dorothy Murray, PuX-088 - PuX-091; 4 negatives (Box 2)
  - Canoeing, PuX-090 - PuX-091; 4 negatives (Box 2)
  - At Concert, PuX-092 (Box 2)
  - Group At Concert, PuX-093 (Box 2)
  - Mrs. Naismith, PuX-094 - PuX-095; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Edward Norris Tarbell Medallion awarded to James Naismith, PuX-096 (Box 2)
  - Nickel Hops, PuX-097 - PuX-110; 13 negatives (Box 2)
  - Sackett, PuX-111 - PuX-124; 14 negatives (Box 2)
  - Delta Theta Delta Mascot (dog), PuX-124 - PuX-125; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Sigma Phi Epsilon Mascot (dog), PuX-126; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Sigma Alpha Epsilon Mascot (dog), PuX-127 - PuX-128; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Sigma Nu Mascot (dog), PuX-129 (Box 2)
  - Library interior, PuX-130; 1 negative and 1 print (Box 2-3)
  - Eager Beavers, PuX-131 (Box 2)
  - Rally Squad, PuX-132 (Box 2)
  - Rook Lid, PuX-133 - PuX-134; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Mixer Dance, PuX-136 - PuX-137; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Multnomah Stadium, PuX-139 (Box 2)
  - Crowd at Multnomah Stadium, PuX-140 - PuX-141; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - OSC Band, PuX-142 (Box 2)
  - Hacking, PuX-143 - PuX-144; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Sigma Phi Epsilon Living Room, PuX-145 (Box 2)
  - Library, PuX-146 - PuX-149; 3 negatives (Box 2)
    Images PuX-146, PuX-148, and PuX-149 available online.
  - Memorial Union, PuX-150 (Box 2)
  - Spring football rally -crowd and Jim Spetz, PuX-177 (Box 2)
  - Spring football rally - Football Queen, PuX-178 (Box 2)
  - Spring football rally - crowd and Jim Spetz, PuX-179 - PuX-180; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - The TAXI Roman Holiday, PuX-181 - PuX-188; 8 negatives (Box 2)
  - Fall 1949 Cover, PuX-215; 2 negatives (Box 2)
    Copy negatives of print of unidentified woman.
- Miscellaneous, 1949; Series VIII; 24 negatives
  Series VIII includes various images, including several images taken for the Phi Delta Theta fraternity. It also includes images of the first Memorial Union Camera Club exhibit.
  - Fashion pictures for Mado, PuMi-001 - PuMi-003; 3 negatives (Box 2)
  - Tech Record cover, PuMi-004 - PuMi-006; 3 negatives (Box 2)
  - Cover Phi Delta Rushing Pamphlet, PuMi-007 - PuMi-008; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Phi Delta Lettermen, PuMi-009; 3 negatives (Box 2)
  - Phi Delta Rushing Pamphlet, 1949; PuMi-010; 6 negatives (Box 2)
  - First Annual Memorial Union Camera Club Exhibit, PuMi-011; 6 negatives (Box 2)
- Dances, 1948; Series IX; 23 negatives
  Series IX consists primarily of group photographs of attendees at the dances and includes a few images of couples dancing.
  - Dolan Hall Dance, CMDA-017 - CMDA-025; 9 negatives (Box 2)
  - Central Hall Dance, CMDA-026 - CMDA-029; 4 negatives (Box 2)
  - Theta Xi Dance, April 17, 1948; CMDA-030 - CMDA-035; 6 negatives (Box 2)
  - Pi Beta Phi house dance, November 13, 1948; CMDA-036 - CMDA-039; 4 negatives (Box 2)
- Memorial Union, circa 1950; Series X; 123 photographs
  The Memorial Union photographs depict Memorial Union officers and various activities and special events offered by the Memorial Union, including the annual Christmas party.
  - Joy Reynolds, Memorial Union Activity Council, PUM-001 (Box 2)
  - Jack Lee, Memorial Union Activity Council, PUM-002 (Box 2)
  - Mary L. Gilfillan, Memorial Union Activity Council, PUM-003 (Box 2)
  - Hern Kaiser, Memorial Union Activity Council, PUM-004 (Box 2)
  - Dan Thomas, Memorial Union Activity Council, PUM-005 (Box 2)
  - Tim Dunn, Memorial Union Activity Council, PUM-006 (Box 2)
  - Paul Moser, Memorial Union Activity Council, PUM-007 (Box 2)
  - Jim Gray, Memorial Union Activity Council, PUM-008 (Box 2)
  - Bob Reeves, Memorial Union Activity Council, PUM-009 (Box 2)
  - Normettia Ellis, Memorial Union activity Council, PUM-010 (Box 2)
  - Memorial Union Activity Council, PUM-011 (Box 2)
  - Virginia Johnson, Memorial Union Activity Council, PUM-012 (Box 2)
  - Senator Wayne Morse, PUM-013 - PUM-016; 4 negatives (Box 2)
  - Charlie Petersen and Mary Lehr, PUM-017 (Box 2)
  - Charlie Petersen and Mrs. Johnson, PUM-018 (Box 2)
  - Charlie Petersen and President Strand, PUM-019 (Box 2)
  - Charlie Petersen Exhibition, PUM-020 (Box 2)
  - Rembrandt Etching, PUM-021 - PUM-023; 3 negatives (Box 2)
  - Christmas Table Decoration, PUM-024 (Box 2)
  - Christmas Decorations, PUM-025 - PUM-027 (Box 2)
    3 negatives
  - Christmas Decorations, Lounge, PUM-028 - PUM-029; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Christmas Decorations, Vestibule, PUM-030 - PUM-031; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Carol Singing, PUM-032 - PUM-034; 3 negatives (Box 2)
  - Tea Room at Christmas Party, PUM-035 (Box 2)
  - Christmas Party, PUM-036 - PUM-038; 3 negatives (Box 2)
  - Bob Shilleriff, Memorial Union Activities Council, PUM-039; 4 negatives (Box 2)
  - Doug McKay Invitation, PUM-040 - PUM-041; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - President Strand Birthday, PUM-042 (Box 2)
  - Dalton Johnson, PUM-043 (Box 2)
  - Spring Salon, PUM-044 (Box 2)
  - Jam Session, PUM-045 - PUM-047; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Cleaner Figures, PUM-048; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Picture Hanging, PUM-049 (Box 2)
  - Dark Room, PUM-050 (Box 2)
  - Listening Room, PUM-051 (Box 2)
  - Dining Service, PUM-052 (Box 2)
  - Chess Players, PUM-053 (Box 2)
  - Dance Band, PUM-054 (Box 2)
  - Organ, PUM-055 (Box 2)
  - Piano, PUM-056 (Box 2)
  - Poster Painting, PUM-057 (Box 2)
  - Tours, PUM-058 (Box 2)
  - Fireplace, PUM-059 (Box 2)
  - Program Consultant, PUM-060 (Box 2)
  - Sunrise Service, PUM-061 - PUM-062; 4 negatives and 1 digital print (Box 2-3)
  - Memorial Vestibule, PUM-063 (Box 2)
  - Final Exams, PUM-064 (Box 2)
  - Portrait Night, PUM-065 (Box 2)
  - Swimming Pool, PUM-066 (Box 2)
  - Table Tennis, PUM-067 (Box 2)
  - Movies, PUM-068 (Box 2)
  - Square Dancing, PUM-069 (Box 2)
  - Memorial Union at Night, PUM-070; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Bob Knoll, PUM-071 (Box 2)
  - Cover for Pictorial, PUM-072 (Box 2)
  - Other Pictures for Cover, PUM-074; 8 negatives (Box 2)
  - CO-OP, PUM-075 (Box 2)
  - The "O", PUM-076 (Box 2)
  - Ballroom, PUM-077 (Box 2)
  - Planning Conference, PUM-078 (Box 2)
  - Front of Memorial Union, PUM-079 - PUM-082; 4 negatives (Box 2)
  - Unidentified Students, PUM-083; 6 negatives (Box 2)
  - Toast Masters, PUM-084; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Pillars of Memorial Union for calendar, PUM-085; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Planning Conference, PUM-086 - PUM-097; 19 photographs (Box 2)
- Oregon Stater, 1948-2005; Series XI; 263 photographs
  The Oregon Stater photographs document student activities and campus events. Many of the images were published in the alumni magazine. The photographs include images of homecoming events, commencement, and athletic facilities and events. Of special note are images of Oregon State faculty that were published on covers of the Stater in 1952-1953. Prints made by Gilkey in 2005 are included.
  - Peterson, 1948; PuO-001 (Box 2)
  - Crandell and Peterson, 1948; PuO-002; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Cliff Crandell, 1948; PuO-003 (Box 2)
  - Registration for Homecoming, 1948; PuO-004; 5 negatives (Box 2)
  - OSC Foundation Committee, 1948; PuO-005 (Box 2)
  - Varsity O Mascot, WSU Game, 1948; PuO-006 (Box 2)
  - Homecoming Luncheon at Armory, 1948; PuO-007; 4 negatives (Box 2)
  - Homecoming Queen Court, 1948; PuO-008 (Box 2)
  - Rook Bonfire, 1949; PuO-009 (Box 2)
  - SAE Homecoming Sign, 1949; PuO-010 (Box 2)
  - Alpha Phi Homecoming Sign, 1949; PuO-011 (Box 2)
  - Homecoming Queen Sally Reymers, 1947; PuO-012 (Box 2)
  - ROTC Honor Studio, 1948; PuO-013 (Box 2)
  - Electrical Engineering Building, 1948; PuO-014 (Box 2)
  - Ski Class, 1948; PuO-015 - PuO-016; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Golf and Tennis Players, PuO-017; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Scarecrow, 1948; PuO-018; 3 negatives (Box 2)
  - Varsity "O" at Basketball Game, 1948; PuO-019 (Box 2)
  - Bob Knoll and John Fenner, PuO-020; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Two Oregon State students, Chuck Sauvain and Dolores Erickson, on lower campus, 1948; PuO-021 - PuO-024; 4 negatives (Box 2)
    Published on cover of May 1948 Oregon Stater.
  - Oscar Paulson, graduating with degree in engineering, and his 4-year-old son Stevie on steps inside Memorial Union, 1948; PuO-025 - PuO-027; 3 negatives (Box 2)
    Published on cover of June 1948 Oregon Stater.
  - Memorial Union Background for June cover, 1948; PuO-028 (Box 2)
  - Commencement, 1948; PuO-029 - PuO-031; 3 negatives (Box 2)
  - Practice Teaching, PuO-032 - PuO-033; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Alumni Board of Directors, 1948; PuO-035; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Homecoming, 1948; PuO-036; 5 negatives (Box 2)
  - Queen Connie Coon and Orchid Lea from Honolulu, OSC Alum, PuO-037; 6 negatives (Box 2)
  - Three basketball players; Crandall, Rinerarson, and Ballantyne, 1948; PuO-038; 2 negatives (Box 2)
    Published on cover of January 1949 Oregon Stater.
  - Championship Basketball Banquet, 1949; PuO-039; 6 negatives (Box 2)
  - Sackett Hall Bedrooms, PuO-040; 3 negatives (Box 2)
  - Sackett Hall Desks, PuO-041; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Sackett Hall Dining Room, PuO-042 (Box 2)
  - Sackett Hall Kitchenette, PuO-043 (Box 2)
  - Sackett Hall Sunporch, PuO-044; 5 negatives (Box 2)
  - Sackett Hall Fireplace, PuO-045; 3 negatives (Box 2)
  - Basketball Pavilion, PuO-046; 3 negatives (Box 2)
  - Art Dept. Pulling Etching, PuO-047 (Box 2)
  - Art Dept. Drawing, PuO-048; 4 negatives (Box 2)
  - Art Dept. Clay Modeling, PuO-049 (Box 2)
  - Art Dept. Painting, PuO-050; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Art Dept. Metal Work, PuO-051; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Art Dept. Interior Decoration, PuO-052; 2 negatives (Box 2)
  - Marlyn Melson, 1949; PuO-053; 2 negatives (Box 2)
    May 1949 cover